Guide to the De Pichon Family Papers, 1711-1907
Department of Special Collections
De Pichon Family Papers,
1711-1907
Special Collections M0563
de Pichon family
28 folders.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Suzanne de Pichon, 1991.
Scope and Content
Family documents, including birth, baptism, school records, marriage, nobility, and death certificates. There are also French legal documents concerning a lawsuit, 1828-1830, 18th century property documents, 18th century passports, and a family tree.
Access Terms
Pichon family; France--Social life and customs.
Container List
- Colegio Aveledo (Aveledo School) in Caracas, Venezuela. Spanish, 1891-1892.At 12 and 14 years old. Javier Pichon took latin and greek grammar, and mathematics, and passed all exams., (3 certificates). (Folder 1)
- Birth Certificate of Marie Amand Maurice Vivier, 1886from Antwerp. Copy dated December 24, 1936. (Folder 2)
- Birth Certificates from Bordeaux for Amadée Pichón, Sept. 13, 1837and for Paul William de Pichón, May 24, 1836. (Folder 3)
- Baptism certificates for William Paul Louis Pichón and Amedée Pichón (son and daughter of Eutrope Francois Xavier Pichón and Marie-Franciose Montamat) on Jan. 26, 1842. (Folder 4)
- Extrait des registres des actes d'etat civil de la Commune de Saintes. Extracts from the civil registers of the town of Saintes. One refers to the marriage of Genevieve Vivier (1908)and the other to the marriage between Elizabeth Vallemant with Eutrope Barnabé Pichon (occurred on July 30, 1770). These are copies of official information. (Folder 5)
- Eutrope Francios Xavier Pichon will be in charge of the Civil Administration office of Merignac (France) from Nov. 1840.French, Oct. 24, 1840. (Folder 6)
- Death certificate for Marie Franciose Montamat widow of Eutrope Francois Xavier Pichon, 1875.Taken from the civil registers of the French Consulate General in Caracas, Venezuela. (Folder 7)
- Passport for Armando de Pichón for travel to France. April 5, 1872.Expedited from Caracas, Venezuela. (Folder 8)
- This is the old piece of the group, written on skin. It has something to do with Pierre and Josué Pichón and a piece of property in St. Thomas (it is not clear if it is the island of St. Thomas or a small town in France). It appears that it could be a will or a transferral of property of some kind. French, 1711. (Folder 9)
- Refers to Eutrope Francoise Xavier Pichon. French, July 21, 1775.Would take more time for a precise translation. (Folder 10)
- Legal documents on law suit against Pierre Javier Pichon. Various other papers which appear to be related. Franch, 1828-1830., 7 pieces. (Folder 11)
- Description of various landholdings with names of owners and/or people living on lands. Boundaries are indicated. This is interesting because it describes the holdings of a fiefdom. (Folder 12)
- Marriage contract between Nicholas Carrouge de Morigny and Marie Antoinette Gabriel la Peyre. French, April 16, 1786. (Folder 13)
- Xavier de Pichon's diploma from the Central University, Caracs, Venezuela for a degree as a Public Land Surveyor (Agrimensor Público). Spanish, Feb. 18, 1894. (Folder 14)
- Xavier de Pichon, diploma from the Central University, Caracas, Venezuela for the degree of Bachelor of Arts and Sciences. Spanish, July 22, 1896. (Folder 15)
- Birth Certificate of Xavier de Pichon, receipt enclosed. French, May 18, 1878. (Folder 16)
- Xavier de Pichon, certificate of approved examinations from the Central University, Caracas, Venezuela for degree in Civil Engineering. Spanish, Feb. 21, 1906.Exam was taken Aug. 10, 1896. (Folder 17)
- Medal of Honor for Public Instruction to Armando de Pichón, Caracas, Venezuela. Spanish, July 15, 1886.And: From the Ministry of the Interior, condecoration of Armando de Pichón with Busto de el Libertador, one of the important national merit awards. Spanish, July 6, 1886. (Folder 18)
- Passport expedited by US Consulate in France to Eutrope Pichon for travel with his wife and children. Sept. 13, 1807. (Folder 19)
- Mimeographed letter from M. Paez Pumar, director of Colegio Aveledo in Caracas to Xavier de Pichon in El Paso, Texas. Spanish, Oct. 22, 1907.Enclosed with letter is a copy of a speech presented by Xavier de Pichon in Colegio Aveledo, Aug. 4, 1907.It is probably a speech he gave at a graduation or celebration of the school and deals with topics such as science and the work of the director. (Folder 20)
- Re: Pierre Xavier Pichon. French, dated in Saintes, April 23, 1877.Baptism records, record referring to birth of Eutrope Pichon on Oct. 12, 1773. (Folder 21)
- Certificate of nationality for Xavier de Pichon. French and Spanish, July 4, 1892. (Folder 22)
- Certificate of Burial for Armando de Pichón in the General Cemetary of South Caracas. Spanish, Oct. 24, 1889. (Folder 23)
- Various extracts of entitlement of nobility, appointment to Director of Finance. Information dates from 1773but was compiled at the French consulate in Caracas. Spanish, June 5, 1877. (Folder 24)
- French passport for Armando de Pichón. French, Nov. 27, 1873. (Folder 25)
- Certificate of completion of primary studies by Louis Joseph Vivier. (Academie le Paris, Department de la Seine). French, July 5, 1898. (Folder 26)
- Marriage license between Xavier de Pichón (25) and Margarite Vivier (17). English, Sept. 24, 1903. (Folder 27)
- Family Tree. (Folder 28)